Now before we continue using that token we store in our redux store,
imdi bu jetonu kullanmaya devam etmeden nce, redux maazamzda saklanmadan
you might remember that when we do sign in and we inspect the data we get back
nce, oturum atmzda ve geri aldmz verileri incelediimizde, bunu hzl
so let me quickly do this, switch to sign in, there
bir ekilde yapmama izin verin, oturum amaya
we also get this expiresIn value.
geelim, ite bu sona erer .
So the token is only valid for 60 minutes, after that
Bu nedenle, jeton sadece 60 dakika geerlidir, bundan sonra
whenever we send it to any resource which requires a token, the request will fail as if we had sent no
bir jeton gerektiren herhangi bir kaynaa gnderdiimiz zaman, istek hibir ekilde hibir belirte
token at all.
gndermemi gibi baarsz olur.
Now this is not the best user experience,
imdi bu en iyi kullanc
we probably want to actively log the user out after this hour.
deneyimi deil, muhtemelen bu saatten sonra kullancy aktif olarak kaydetmek istiyoruz.
As a side note, if the user reloads the application the state is lost anyway because that clears the
Bir yan not olarak, kullanc uygulamay yeniden yklyorsa, durum yine de
redux store since the entire application reloads,
kaybolur nk bu, tm uygulama
so there, we can then change the UI anyways which we'll do in the future to show that we're not logged
yeniden yklendiinden redux deposunu temizler, bylece, gelecekte UI'yi deitirebiliriz. 'Giri
in but it is the state that we are logged in and don't reload the page for an hour where we can get in
yapmadnz, ancak giri yaptmz ve sayfay gremediimiz bir zamana sahip olabileceimiz
this strange spot of having a token which is not valid anymore without us seeing that.
bu tuhaf noktaya ulaabileceimiz bir saat iin sayfay yeniden yklemememiz.
For that reason what I want to do is, I want to add some code to invalidate that token after one hour
Bu nedenle yapmak istediim ey, bir saat sonra jetonu geersiz klmak iin bir kod
so that we then can also update our UI
eklemek istiyorum. Bylece, simge
once the token is no longer there. To do that, I'll go into my auth actions file and I'll add a new constant,
artk belirte artk yokken UI'mz da gncelleyebiliriz. Bunu yapmak iin, auth eylemler dosyama gideceim ve
a new function essentially which I'll name checkAuthTimeout, there
yeni bir sabit, yeni bir ilev ekleyeceim esasen checkAuthTimeout ismini vereceim, orada
I expect to get the expiration time and in there, I will return this function where I get dispatch as
sona erme sresini elde etmeyi bekliyorum ve orada bu ilevi dndreceim Baz async kodlarn altrmak istediim
an argument because I want to run some async code.
iin argman olarak gnderdiim yer.
I will dispatch this checkAuthTimeout action when we get back a success response,
Bir baar cevabn geri aldmzda bu checkAuthTimeout eylemini gndereceim,
so where I'll also dispatch authSuccess, I'll also dispatch checkAuthTimeout
bylece authSuccess' da gndereceim, ayrca checkAuthTimeout'u gnderiyorum
and I will pass on response data
ve yant verisini ileteceim
and there, it's this
ve orada, bu
expiresIn property you saw, expiresIn,
expiresIn zelliini grdnzde, expiresIn, hzlca
you can quickly see that if we log in again, switch to sign in,
tekrar giri yaparsak oturum amak iin
I'm talking about this property expiresIn. That holds a value,
bu mlk hakknda konuuyorum. Bu bir deer, bir say ya
a number or to be precise, a string but which can be parsed as a number and I get this here,
da kesin, bir dize, ancak bir say olarak ayrtrlabilir ve bunu burada
there I now want to call setTimeout and execute a function after a certain amount of time
alabilirim, burada setTimeout'u armak ve belirli bir sre sonra bir ilevi yrtmek istiyorum ve muhtemelen tahmin
and you can probably guess which amount of time, the expiration time here.
edebilirsiniz. hangi zaman sresi, burada sona erme zaman.
Now here in setTimeout, I want to do something and I simply want to call logout,
imdi burada setTimeout'ta bir ey yapmak istiyorum ve sadece k yapmak istiyorum, bu zaten ihtiyacm
this is a new action I need anyway.
olan yeni bir hareket.
So I'll export a constant which I'll name
Bu yzden, buradan
logout here, will be an action which doesn't take any input, will be a synchronous action creator,
k yapaca bir sabiti vereceim, herhangi bir girdi almayan bir eylem olacak, ezamanl bir
I'll set the type to a type I have yet to create
eylem yaratcs olacak, tr henz oluturmamam gereken
so let's create it now, in action types I'll export a constant AUTH_LOGOUT with the identifier AUTH_LOGOUT
bir tre ayarlayacam imdi olutur, ilem trlerinde AUTH_LOGOUT tanmlaycs ile sabit bir AUTH_LOGOUT vereceim ve imdi
and now with that, I can dispatch this action so here the type will be actionTypes.AUTH_LOGOUT and this
bununla birlikte bu eylemi gnderebilirim, bylece buradaki tip actionTypes olacaktr. AUTH_LOGOUT ve bu k eylemi, bu
logout action, this action creator here will also be used in setTimeout of checkAuthTimeout.
eylem yaratcs burada checkAuthTimeout setTimeout esinde de kullanlacaktr.
So here I would call dispatch after the expiration time to call the logout action, like this, always
Bu nedenle, k sresinin sona ermesinden sonra, rnein, bu ilevleri yerine getirmesi iin gnderim
execute these functions because that then returns the action which is actually dispatched.
ars gnderirim, nk bu, daha sonra gnderilmekte olan eylemi dndrr.
So now with that, we execute or we dispatch the logout function after that time span and that allows
imdi bununla birlikte, o zaman aralndan sonra k ilevini yrtyoruz veya gnderiyoruz ve
me to now go into my reducer and there, handle the logout case.
bu da imdi redktrmn iine girmeme izin veriyor.
So I'll add a new function in there which I'll name authLogout, I get state and action here
Bu yzden ben orada authLogout adn adlandracam yeni bir ilev ekleyeceim, burada ve ilevde durumu ve
and in the function, I'll return an updated javascript object and that updated javascript object here
durumu alyorum, gncellenmi bir javascript nesnesi dndreceim ve burada gncellenen javascript nesnesi elbette updateObject ile
will of course be created with updateObject
oluturulacaktr benim eski durumumu
is my old state where I set the token to null and the user id to null so that I am essentially logged
null olarak belirlediim ve kullanc kimliimi null olarak belirleyemem, bylece oturum am olduum kullanc tarafndan
out because all that core information that made up a logged in user is now lost again. And I need to
oluturulan tm temel bilgiler artk kaybedildi. Ve elbette bununla
handle that of course here, case actionTypes.AUTH_LOGOUT, there I want to return the result of the auth
baa kmak zorundaym, dava actionTypes. AUTH_LOGOUT, burada durum ve eylemi argman
logout function where I pass state and action as arguments and with that, we got this timer in place
olarak geirdiim auth k ilevinin sonucunu dndrmek istiyorum ve bununla birlikte,
in our action creator's file in checkAuthTimeout which will fire after whatever firebase returns
bu zamanlaycy bizim action creator'umuzdaki checkAuthTimeout dosyasnda bulduk. daha
us and which will then ensure that the user is logged out.
sonra kullancnn oturumu kapattndan emin olun.
And for now, this will clear the store and not do much else,
Ve imdilik, bu, maazadan temizlenecek ve baka
it won't show any visual feedback but we will implement something to happen when the user logs out
bir ey yapamayacak, herhangi bir grsel geri bildirimi gstermeyecek, ancak kullanc, kullancnn kastl
including when he deliberately logs out to give the user a clue that he's not logged in anymore.
olarak oturum ap kapatmadn belirten kullanc oturumunu atnda bir eyler uygulayacaz. artk giri yapm.
For now, let's see if that dispatching all works, switch to sign in and submit, let's have a look at redux,
imdilik, tm almalarn gnderilip gnderilmediini, gnderilip gnderilmediine, bir daha gzden geirip bakmayacana
there
bakalm,
I'm actually immediately logged out
ite aslnda hemen ktm,
so somehow, this fired a bit too early.
bu biraz fazla erken kt.
The reason of course is expiration time is 3600
Tabii ki son kullanma sresi 3600'dr ancak setTimeout
but setTimeout expects to get milliseconds
milisaniyeyi almay beklemektedir, bu yzden
so it was only 3.6 seconds.
sadece 3'tr. 6 saniye.
It's a good practice,
Bu iyi
now we can at least see that authLogout is dispatched and that it did clear the tokens and user ID
bir uygulama, imdi en azndan authLogout'un gnderildiini ve belirtelerin ve kullanc kimliinin
but of course, I want to multiply this value with one thousand to turn my milliseconds to real seconds,
ak olduunu grebiliyoruz ama tabii ki, bu deeri milisaniyemi gerek saniyeye evirmek iin bin katna karmak istiyorum,
so now it should be one hour.
bu yzden imdi bir saat.
Now if I save this and do this exercise again, log in, switch to sign in,
imdi bunu kaydedip tekrar bu altrmay yaparsam giri yapn, oturum amaya gein, imdi authLogout'u
now we shouldn't see authLogout because now we could wait for an hour, I'm not going to do that here,
grmemeliyiz nk imdi bir saat kadar bekleyebiliriz, bunu burada yapmayacam, bunu yapmaktan
feel free to do so of course.
ekinmeyin tabii ki.
We can now continue
imdi devam edebiliriz
and now finally take advantage of our token to protect some of the resources on our backend in the
ve nihayet, arka ucumuzdaki kaynaklarn bir ksmn ilk etapta korumak, ardndan
first place then still reach them
da onlara ulamak ve daha
and then of course also update our UI to for example add a logout button to allow the user to logout
sonra UI'muzu gncellemek iin kullanc arabirimimizi gncellemek iin kullanacaz. ve
and stuff like that.
onun gibi eyler.
So these will be the next steps I'll work on,
Yani bunlar zerinde alacam sonraki admlar olacak,
let's do that in the next lectures.
bir sonraki derslerde bunu yapalm.